《超感警探》前情提要
Previously on "The Mentalist"...
我們有個撲克牌局
Listen, there's this poker game we've got going on.
-想來嗎  -也許吧  什么時候
- You want in? - Maybe. When?
我想想  星期四晚
Let me see-- Thursday night.
你要去玩撲克
You're going to play poker.
特蕾莎  很高興你來了
Hey. Teresa. Glad you made it.
-這位是地檢官唐·沃爾科特  -您好
- This is District Attorney Don Wolcott. - Hi.
聯調局局長查爾斯·貝利
FBI Bureau Director Charles Bailey.
-您好  -參議員艾琳·道金斯
- Sir. - Senator Eileen Dawkins.
是州議員
State Senator.
來了這么多高層人士
It's a pretty high-class crowd.
你早跟我說一聲就好了
I wish you would have warned me.
我想這位你認識  對嗎
Oh, I think you know this guy, right?
特蕾莎  我沒想過你會喜歡賭博
Teresa. I didn't take you for a gambler.
如果知道自己贏定了  就不算是賭了
It's not gambling if you know you're gonna win.
紅心A
Ace of hearts.
不跟
Not me.
法官先生  看你的了
Action's on you, Judge.
那就
Well...
五百美元
$500.
莊家封牌
Dealer folds.
伯特侖  比你多了五百美元
That's $500 more to you, Bertram.
加注一千
Raise it $1,000.
你在虛張聲勢
You're bluffing.
全押上
All in.
我喜歡跟你打牌  蓋爾
I love playing with you, Gale.
看透你就跟讀兒童讀物一樣容易
I can read you like a kids' book.
隨你說  拿走你的籌碼吧
Yeah, yeah. Just pick up your chips.
"晚安  月亮"
"Goodnight moon."
源自美國兒童讀物《晚安  月亮》
抱歉  失陪了各位  有個案子
I'm sorry, guys, but we caught one.
-能幫我兌現嗎  -好的
- Will you cash me out? - Yeah.
玩得愉快
Have fun.
北加州大學  自然歷史博物館
你在這
There you are.
沒尸體的時候
I should come by sometime
我也該常來這里看看
when there's not a corpse here to meet us.
你又去玩撲克了嗎  里斯本
Are you playing poker again, Lisbon?
你被撲克打垮了
It's getting the better of you.
輸錢了
Losing money?
腿毛都輸光了
Losing skin's more like it.
伯特侖狀態不好
Bertram's been in a bad mood.
你好  我是加調局的里斯本探員
Hi. I'm Agent Lisbon with the CBI.
克里斯托·帕帕達基斯
Christos Papadakis.
我是校自然科學系主任
I am Dean of the university's Natural Science Department,
博物館是由我負責的
So... the museum is my responsibility.
請跟我來
Please follow me.
你們就是上次調查
I believe your team is the one
門特洛教授遇害案的小組吧
who investigated the death of professor Montero.
是的
Yeah, we were.
要走一段路
We have a bit of a walk.
博物館的實驗室在東翼
The museum labs are in the east wing of the museum.
對死者的情況你有多少了解
What can you tell us about the victim?
我們認為死者是琳達·帕弗瑞
We think it is Linda Parfrey.
你們認為是她
You think it's her?
琳達失蹤了好一陣子了  而且...
Linda has been missing for some time, and...
你們很快就知道了
Well, you'll see.
這位是發現琳達的學生
Ah, this is the student who found Linda.
告訴他們你的名字
Tell--tell them your name.
我叫格雷  格雷戈里·劉易斯
Uh, Greg. Uh, Gregory Lewis.
我是大約午夜的時候發現她的
I found her around midnight.
說說事發經過
Tell me what happened.
全憑運氣  我找到了一只非常好的樹鼩
Well, by sheer luck, I-I happened upon a very nice tree shrew.
我從未研究過樹鼩
Um, I've never examined one before,
就把它帶回來準備去除皮肉
and I-I brought it in to strip the flesh off.
就是只保留骨架
You know, to keep the skeleton.
這怎么做
How do you do that?
把它們放到這些箱子里
Oh, w-we put 'em in these tanks.
這又怎么把骨架和皮肉分離開來
How does that strip them of their flesh?
-食尸蟲  -食尸蟲  對
- Flesh-eating bugs. - Flesh-eating bugs. Right.
沒錯
Right.
我就是這樣發現琳達的
That's when I found linda.
沒事了
Oh! Okay.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
僅供學習 禁止用于任何商業盈利行為
更多影視更新
請登陸www.YYeTs.com
翻譯：灰灰是菇涼 非燕 那時花開 Bony Michael 面條打包子  時間軸：玖月
超感警探
第五季
第十四集
時間軸：煙幕遲遲   校對：灰灰是菇涼  非燕  Bony  王小麥
特效&后期：灰灰是菇涼   總監：灰灰是菇涼
失蹤  琳達·帕弗瑞
對  是琳達的戒指
Yeah, that's Linda's ring, all right.
那死者就是琳達·帕弗瑞
So it is Linda Parfrey.
為何要棄尸于蟲箱里
Why dump a body into a beetle tank?
博物館安保措置不佳
The museum doesn't have great security,
但也沒到能隨隨便便把尸體運出去的地步
but it's not the kind of place you can sneak a body out of.
除非尸體小到能裝進行李袋
Unless you make it small enough to fit in a duffel bag.
兇手是在等蟲子將尸體啃食至
So the killer was waiting for the bugs to eat it
只剩骨架  然后再偷運出去
down to the skeleton so they could sneak it out?
有可能  我們在箱子里發現了一件科學器械
Possibly. Uh, we found a scientific tool in the tank.
有可能是兇器
It could be the murder weapon.
兇手也許也是一名科學家
So the killer's probably another scientist then.
或者是博物館的工作人員
Or someone that works at the museum.
最后一次看見琳達是什么時候
When was Linda last seen?
琳達已經失蹤好幾星期了
Linda's been missing a couple weeks.
大家以為她是去
People thought she was out camping
約塞米蒂國家公園做什么研究去了
near Yosemite doing some kind of research.
后來有人注意到她的車停在校園里
Then someone noticed her car was on campus,
才意識到她失蹤了
and they realized she was missing.
是誰填的失蹤人口報告
Who filed the missing persons report?
索尼亞·基德博士
Dr. Sonia Kidd.
她是校生物系主任
Head of the Biology Department at the university
也是琳達的顧問
and Linda's adviser.
名字聽起來很耳熟
Her name sounds familiar.
是的  她寫過幾本書
Yeah, she's written a couple books.
流行科學讀物  有一本叫
Popular science stuff. One's called
《天生殺手:謀殺的進化根源》
"Natural born killers: The evolutionary roots of murder."
有趣  我和簡去找她談談
Cute. Jane and I will go talk to her.
琳達在博物館有間辦公室
And, uh, Linda had an office here at the museum.
你和周去查看一下
You and Cho check it out.
收到  頭兒
You got it, boss.
我們以為她在山里迷路了
We thought she was lost in the mountains.
沒想到她一直都在這里
But she was here the whole time.
簡直太可怕了
It's too horrible for words.
她研究什么  研究哪種動物
What did she study? What kind of animal?
有什么關系嗎
Why does that matter?
沒有人會因為偶然而選擇其終身事業
Nobody picks what they dedicate their life to by accident.
都是有原因的
It says something.
我研究靈長類動物大腦
I study primate brains.
這能說明我是怎樣的人
What does that say about me?
你有一些陰暗的思想
You have dark thoughts inside your head
但你覺得它們很正常很自然
that you want to believe are normal and natural.
當然它們確實是那樣
Which they are, of course.
琳達是研究鳥類的
Linda was an ornithologist.
她的博士生項目是研究北撲翅鴷的飲食
Her doctorate was on the diet of the northern flicker.
北撲翅鴷是一種啄木鳥
A kind of woodpecker.
有意思
Interesting.
啄木鳥十分執著
Tenacious.
不斷用頭撞樹直到問題解決
Bang their head against the problem until they solve it.
琳達也是這種性格嗎
Was that Linda?
是的
It was.
但是啄木鳥并不是用頭撞樹
Although woodpeckers don't bang their heads
而是用喙在樹上鉆洞
against things so much as they use their bills to drill holes.
的確  潛意識這東西
Yes. Well, the subconscious mind is--
沒那么準
isn't really a stickler about that kind of thing.
她是個好學生嗎
Uh, was she a good student?
她很聰明
Brilliant.
她已經和人合作在著名期刊上
She had already co-authored several papers
發表了好幾篇論文了
in prestigious journals.
有誰嫉妒她嗎
Well, who was jealous?
沒有
Nobody.
我們的生物系在整個西海岸是頂尖的
This is the top biology department on the west coast.
這里的人都是精英
Best and brightest only.
每一個人的成功對我們都有好處
The success of one of us helps all of us.
我們是一家人
We're a family.
每天都有謀害親人的事發生
Well, people murder family members every day.
這很自然
It's natural.
謀殺是一件自然的事
Murder is natural.
但卻不正常
But abnormal.
教授們不會了解丑聞
Teachers don't know there's scandals
除非他們自己深陷其中
unless of course they are the scandal.
你們問完了嗎
Are we done?
暫時問完了
Yeah. For now.
我們得跟幾個學生談談
Uh, we're gonna need to talk to some students
還得去一趟禮品店
and visit the gift shop,
出門左拐  對嗎
which is left out the door, isn't it?
打擾一下  你在做什么
Excuse me. What are you doing?
你們是什么人
Who are you?
我是瑞斯比探員  這位是周探員
I'm Agent Rigsby. This is Agent Cho.
我們是加調局的  你是誰
We're with CBI. And you are?
梅根·帕克
Megan Parker.
我是琳達博士課題的同學
I was Linda's classmate in the doctoral program.
我的辦公室就在隔壁
And I have the office next door.
你在這做什么
What are you doing here?
我想在你們把這里封鎖之前
I just came to get my copy of "Understanding macro-evolution"
拿走我的《理解宏觀進化》的拷貝
before you guys sealed the place off.
你跟琳達熟悉嗎
Did you know Linda well?
她是這里的明星
She was a rock star.
也許需要打扮下  但確實是明星
A rock star who could use a makeover, but still.
她拿到了今年的院長獎學金
She got the Dean's fellowship this year.
大約有10萬塊
That's like 100 grand.
而我們這些人只能用社保金
The rest of us will be paying off our student loans
去交我們的助學貸款
with our social security checks.
怎么會有這么多動物標本
What's with all the taxidermy?
琳達不是研究啄木鳥的嗎
I thought Linda just studied woodpeckers.
管理標本室是琳達勤工儉學的工作
No, Linda managed the specimen rooms for her work-study,
她精力旺盛嘛
so she got the overflow.
毒品嗎
Huh. Drugs?
是糖
Sugar.
她不吸毒
She didn't do drugs.
連無糖汽水也不喝
Not even diet soda.
她的私生活怎么樣
What about her personal life?
-什么意思  -她有男朋友嗎
- What about it? - Did she have one?
我們沒怎么談論過這個話題
We didn't talk about that stuff very much.
我知道她有個校外的男朋友
I know she had a boyfriend outside the school.
但僅此而已
But that's all I know.
簡  收到留言后給我回電話
Hey, Jane, call me when you get this.
我想我找到琳達的同學了
I think I found Linda's classmates.
在大象這邊
Look for the elephants.
大多數的物種在很長一段時間都不進化
Most species stay in stasis for long periods of time.
-抱歉  有什么需要  -我是加調局的里斯本探員
- Sorry, can I help you? - I'm Agent Lisbon with the CBI.
-你是弗里德曼教授嗎  -客座教授
- Professor Friedman? - Adjunct Professor.
對  客座教授保羅·弗里德曼
Yes, Adjunct Professor Paul Friedman,
你也看到了  學生們都對我
which, as you can see, engenders a great deal of respect
非常敬重
from the students.
我在基德教授手下教課
Uh, I teach a couple seminars under Dr. Kidd.
抱歉打斷你了
I'm sorry to interrupt,
我是來調查琳達·帕弗瑞的情況的
but I'm looking for information on Linda Parfrey.
這些都是她的同學  對嗎
These are her classmates, right?
對  我們都認識琳達
Yeah. Uh, we all know Linda.
你們知道什么能協助
Do you know anything that might be helpful
調查的線索嗎
with the investigation?
我們知道琳達有個男友
We know that Linda had a boyfriend.
我們想找他談談
Uh, we'd like to talk to him.
應該是前男友吧
Ex-boyfriend, I guess.
她不怎么談這事  可有一晚在實驗室
She didn't talk much about it, but late one night in the lab,
她告訴我他們分手了
she told me they broke up.
什么時候的事
When was that?
大概是她失蹤前一周
About a week before she went missing.
你不會懷疑是他干的吧
You don't think he did it, do you?
他可是個警察
I mean, he's a cop.
-警察  知道名字嗎  -知道
- A cop? Do you know his name? - Yeah.
舊金山警局的雷·莫蘭警官
Officer Ray Moran, San Francisco P.D.
片警
Beat cop.
好  和他的隊長談談
All right, talk to his captain.
問問能不能把他帶來局里問話
See if we can bring Moran in for an interview.
讓周問話  也叫上簡  如果他來了的話
Put Cho on it. Jane, too, if he ever comes in.
好
You got it.
頭兒
Hey, boss?
我成功了  我考入了培訓計劃
I did it. I made it into the program.
白帽黑客  你考上了  真不錯
White hat? You got in? That's great.
對  在洛杉磯培訓一個月
Yeah. A month in L.A.
雖然我還是會一直盯著電腦屏幕
I'll be staring at a computer screen the whole time,
可還是很棒
but still.
大家都會想你的
The team's gonna miss you.
你說會幫我向伯特侖申請助學金的
You said you'd talk to Bertram about the stipend request.
兩天后就得交保證金了
The deposit's due in two days.
我回去路上會找他
I'll swing by on my way back.
謝了  頭兒
Thanks, boss.
這叫做白帽黑客
It's called white hat.
這是由真正黑客教授的先進的
It's an advanced computer investigation training program
電腦調查培訓項目
taught by actual hackers.
非常高級
It's so advanced,
她給我介紹的時候我都聽不太明白
I don't know what she's saying when she talks about it.
我想馬上申請培訓津貼
I'd like to rush a request for a training stipend
幫她支付培訓費用
to cover the costs.
你覺得曼徹斯特出老千了嗎
You think Manchester's been cheating?
-什么  -打牌時候
- What? - At poker.
沒
No.
他太得意了
Well, he's just s-so damn smug.
《月亮晚安》  他說
You know, "Goodnight moon," he says--
那是什么意思
What the hell is that?
只是打牌而已
It's just a game.
你自己都不信吧
You don't believe that.
長官
Sir...
不  對了  范佩爾是什么事
No--oh, what was that about Van Pelt?
她的培訓津貼
Her training stipend.
時間很緊
Times are tight.
我們砍了所有外部培訓金的預算
We've cut all outside training funds from the budget.
不行  沒法撥款
No, request denied.
里斯本說聯系不上你
Lisbon said she lost you.
我帶了禮物來
Well, I come bearing gifts.
格蕾斯
Grace.
恐龍果凍是給我的
Jelly dinosaurs are for me...
以后吃
For later.
還有...
And...
-我猜你喜歡三角龍  -對
- I'm guessing you're a Triceratops man. - Yeah.
而瑞斯比喜歡霸王龍
Rigsby is a T. Rex.
案情有新進展嗎
Any news on the case?
有  死者的前男友是舊金山警察
Yeah, the victim's ex-boyfriend is an S.F.P.D. beat cop.
現在正在巡邏  我正要去找他問話
He's on patrol right now. I was just gonna go talk to him.
-出警嗎  -對
- On the streets? - Yeah.
走吧  我有段時間沒出警了
Let's go. I haven't been on the streets for a while.
走吧
Let's do it.
-走吧  -不謝我嗎
- Come on. - Thanks?
我不知道  他大概五尺六
I don't know. He was like, uh, 5'6".
體型不算胖  臉很大
Not fat, really. Just a big face.
棕色頭發
Brown hair.
他都沒有持槍  你為什么給他錢
He didn't even have a gun. Why'd you give him the money?
我沒給他  是他自己拿走的
I didn't give it to him, he took it!
這家伙什么打扮
What was he dressed like, this guy?
你們是加調局的嗎
You guys from CBI?
我是周探員  這位是派翠克·簡
Agent Cho. This is Patrick Jane.
我很愿意配合你們工作
Uh, look, I want to talk to you guys,
可我得先把手頭的事處理完
but we gotta handle this, okay?
我過幾個小時找你們吧
Let me catch up with you in a couple hours.
-幾個小時  -對  我們剛接警
- A couple hours? - Yeah, we just got this.
我們得發布犯罪通報
I mean, we gotta put out a crime broadcast.
還得片區巡邏
We gotta cruise the neighborhood.
然后寫報告
Then there's the paperwork.
你的報告我是愛莫能助了
Well, can't help you with the paperwork.
-他戴著兜帽  走進來  -你為什么把錢給他
- He had a hood. He came in... - Why'd you give him the money?
先生  請由我們來問話
Sir, we're asking the questions here.
告訴我事發經過
Just tell me what happened.
我從收銀機取錢時這家伙走進來
So this dude comes up while I'm cashing out the register,
問我要名片
asks for a calling card.
我只轉過身一秒鐘
I just turned for one second,
他就把手伸進窗口搶了一摞20塊
and he reached through the gap and grabbed a stack of $20s.
你得等到取完鈔
You wait until you're finished cashing out
才能做另一筆交易
before you do another transaction!
聽著  這家伙拿著錢
Look, the guy had money.
他看上去沒什么可疑的
He didn't look shady or anything.
我怎么會知道他會搶錢
How was I supposed to know?
請問
Hey. Excuse me.
給我演示一下他手伸進來夠錢的情景
Show me how he reached through the gap again.
好了  手縮回去
All right. Pull your hand out.
這就是抓浣熊的方法  你知道嗎
That's how they catch a raccoon, you know that?
這么說  那家伙沒法通過這個口搶錢
So the guy couldn't have grabbed the cash through the gap.
根本沒有這個人  是嗎  哥們
There wasn't another guy, was there, buddy?
是你  你就是小偷
You! You're the thief!
我是小偷
I'm the thief?
你就是小偷
You're the thief.
你就付我那么點工資  反倒說我是小偷
With what you're paying me, I'm the thief?
活兒干完了  哥們
Work's done here, buddy.
我想你們可以把小偷帶去做筆錄了
I think you can get your man to do the paperwork.
聽著
Look--
不不不
No, no, no.
你和琳達什么時候認識的
When did you and Linda meet?
去年  我在值夜班
Last year. I was moonlighting,
在博物館做安保
doing security at the museum.
你們的感情生活如何
And how was the relationship?
她的生活比我認識的任何人都穩當
Her life was more together than anybody I ever met.
她很專注
She was so focused.
我想也感染到了我
Got to me, too, I guess.
我甚至開始為警官考試做準備
I even started studying for the sergeant's exam.
然后把她給甩了
Mm-hmm. And then you dumped her?
-你以為我不難過嗎  -這要你告訴我們
- You think I was happy about it? - You tell me.
大約兩個月前  我收到了一封匿名電郵
About two months ago I got an anonymous e-mail
里面有個鏈接
with a link in it
是她網上的約會資料
to her online dating profile.
我無法相信
I couldn't believe it.
她已經在和別人交往了嗎
And she'd started seeing other people?
我不知道有沒有
I... I don't know if she started.
她只是在看有沒有更好的
She was just shopping around.
可能她一直都這樣吧
Maybe she'd been doing it the whole time.
-你和她聊過這事嗎  -聊過
- You talk to her about it? - Yeah.
大吵了一架
Big fight.
你對她動粗了嗎
You get rough with her?
沒  我不干這種事
Mnh. I don't have that in me.
我不會傷害女人  尤其是琳達
Hurt a woman? Especially not Linda.
她有解釋嗎
She have an explanation?
她不承認  不過她還能怎么樣呢
She denied it, you know, but what else was she gonna do?
我無法接受她腳踏兩條船  只好放手了
I can't take cheating. I had to let her go.
你知道資料是誰發給你的嗎
Mm-hmm. Did you know who sent you the profile?
-不知道  -你不好奇嗎
- No. - And you weren't curious?
我不知道  我...
I don't know. I...
某個人的女友和我同病相憐
Some guy's girlfriend's in the same boat as me,
有人心存怨恨
somebody's holding a grudge.
唯一重要的是  我配不上她
Only thing that mattered was I wasn't enough for her.
分手后  你沒再和她聯系過嗎
And after you broke up, you never spoke to her again?
沒
No.
我早該知道的
I should have known.
她很有頭腦
You know, she had smarts.
她會大有作為
She was gonna have a big life.
她怎么會想要我這樣的小人物呢
What'd she want with a mook like me, right?
有什么進展嗎
Do you have something?
這是別人傳給莫蘭的約會資料
Here's the dating profile somebody sent Moran.
東方海灣
查查這個交友網站
Get a hold of the dating site.
看是否有人在她失蹤前后聯系過她
See if anybody contacted her around the time she went missing.
我覺得琳達沒和人約會
I don't think Linda went on any dates.
為什么
Well, why not?
發送莫蘭這封電郵的地址
The address that sent Moran the e-mail
正是建立這個交友賬戶的郵箱地址
was used to set up an account with the dating site.
你找到了嗎
Did you find them?
算是吧  我登陸了賬戶
Sort of. I logged into the account.
你不需要密碼嗎
Don't you need a password for that?
我用最常見的密碼試了兩分鐘
I spent two minutes using the most common passwords.
是"Qwerty"
It was "Qwerty."
"Qwerty"
"Qwerty"?
Q-w-e-r-t-y
Q-w-e-r-t-y.
這是最常見的密碼第五位
It's the fifth most common password.
猜猜是誰的資料
Guess whose profile it was.
琳達
Linda.
那發給莫蘭資料的人就是創建賬戶的人
So whoever sent Moran the profile also created it.
對  資料是偽造的
Yep. Profile's a fake.
有人想拆散琳達和莫蘭警官
Someone was trying to break up Linda and officer Moran.
干得好
Nice work. Mm.
聽著  我知道你沒去成培訓計劃很失望
Look, I know you're disappointed about the training program.
我們明年送你去
We'll get you in next year.
沒事
It's fine.
伯特侖本應該打的得心應手
Bertram's supposed to be this real smooth player,
但他卻輸了好幾把牌
but he loses a couple of hands of poker
還惹惱了跟他打牌的人
and he has to bum everybody else out.
琳達想找一個"身材火辣的男人"
Linda wanted "A man with a super hot body."
你是在說偽造的交友簡介
The fake dating profile, right?
你剛才在說什么
You were saying something?
伯特侖把范佩爾給坑慘了
Bertram hanging Van Pelt out to dry.
他打牌輸了很多錢  就變得歇斯底里了
He's just mad because he's losing big money at poker.
有些人就是喜歡把他們的痛苦凌駕于他人之上
Well, some people like to push their pain onto other people,
軟弱的人  總是有人更軟弱的
weaker people, and there's always someone weaker.
這就是生命的輪回啊
That's just the circle of life.
好吧
Cheery.
里斯本  伯特侖不是想贏  是必須贏
Bertram doesn't want to win, Lisbon, he has to.
所以他才會在現在的位子上
It's why he is where he is.
對他而言  輸是不可忍受的
The idea of losing is just intolerable to him.
為什么會有人想拆散琳達和她男友呢
Why would somebody want to break Linda and her boyfriend up?
情敵
Romantic rivalry?
有可能
Yeah, possibly.
"我在找有頭腦  有肌肉  全面的男人"
"I'm looking for brains, brawn, the total package."
范佩爾試著追蹤電子郵件
Van Pelt's trying to trace the e-mail,
但毫無收獲
but she hit a dead end.
不管是誰做的肯定留下了線索
Well, whoever authored this left their fingerprints all over it.
"半吊子不行"
"No half-steppers.
"我在找一個真正的壞小子
"A genuine badass.
裝點我的小巢"
Feather my nest."
把人都喊來  里斯本
Gather the troops, Lisbon.
為啥
Why?
咱們來玩賓果游戲
It's time to play bingo.
我們從偽造的約會資料里提取了一些詞
So we have a list of words from the fake dating profile.
我們和學生們談談
We talk to the students
對比學生們的用詞
and compare what they say to the words in the list,
如果他們的用詞和列表上的詞相吻合
and if what they say matches up with the words on the list,
那他們就是偽造資料的人嗎
Then they're the one that wrote the profile?
你說的沒錯
So far, so good.
但我們怎么讓他們說出這些詞呢
But how do we get them to say the right words?
我們該問他們些什么
What do we ask them about?
讓他們不停的說話就行了
You have to try to get their words flowing.
-談談他們喜歡的東西  -喜歡的東西
- Talk to them about their passions. - Their passions?
當然是動物
Animals, of course.
蟲子  以及小動物
Bugs. Critters.
人們用"冷血"來表示邪惡
People use "Coldblooded" to mean evil,
就好像物種的體溫調節特性
as if a species' thermophysiology
能夠決定它們的道德屬性一樣
could determine its moral attributes.
這太荒唐了
That's ridiculous.
爬行動物永遠也發明不了原子彈
Reptiles never invented the atomic bomb.
要我說  恒溫動物才是問題的所在
If you ask me, warm blood is the problem.
明白我的意思嗎
Know what I mean?
失陪一下
Excuse me.
說說...骷髏吧
So... skeletons.
你為什么喜歡骷髏
Why are you into them?
為什么一定要有原因呢
Why do I need a reason?
我就當你是不正常了
I'll just go with "Weird."
這就像是在我們的五臟六腑之下
It's, like, under all this viscera we wear,
有一些很強壯  很干凈
there's--well, there's something strong and--and clean
很美麗的東西  把它們組合在了一起
and--and beautiful that--that holds us together.
沒它們還真不行  我覺得這很酷
You can't lose it. I think--I think that's cool.
我通過了嗎
Did I pass?
我之前接受過精神分析測試
I've taken a psych test before.
簡先生
Mr. Jane.
我們剛才還談到了你
We were just discussing you.
帕帕達基斯院長和我說了你驚人的記憶力
Dean Papadakis told me about your impressive memory.
我現在的記憶力大不如前了
My own memory isn't as good as it used to be.
你有什么秘訣嗎
What's your secret?
不要忘記就行了
It's easy to remember when you never forget.
你在做什么
What you doing?
放置捕捉飛蛾的誘餌
Laying bait for moths.
它們喜歡甜味
They like sweetness,
所以我就用芝麻蕉和啤酒做餌
so I use brown bananas and beer.
真美味
Delicious.
保羅在這里發現了一個全新的飛蛾物種
Paul here discovered a new species of moth.
加利福尼亞綠玉蛾
The California Jade Moth.
在我們的博物館里就有展出
It's on display in our museum.
真是件了不起的大事
It's rather a big deal.
是啊  現在世界上的蕓蕓昆蟲又多了一種
Yeah. Now there are 1,500,001 types of insects in the world.
這謙虛可真假
Well, that's false modesty.
我想是的  這的確是件大事
I guess so. It is a big deal.
對研究蛾的人來說
To moth people.
是對我們大家來說
To all of us.
恭喜你獲得新發現
Congratulations on your new addition.
-謝謝  -令人印象深刻
- Thank you. - It's most impressive.
謝謝
Thank you.
讓我猜猜  你是在研究禿鷹
Uh, let me guess. You're studying buzzards,
而你還設好了陷阱
and you're laying a trap for one right now.
說的跟真的一樣
As if.
我研究的是"加州海獅的交配習慣"
Mating habits of the Zalophus Californianus.
海獅
Sea lions.
雄海獅靠打斗吸引一群雌海獅  像個壞小子
One badass male maintaining a stable of females through combat.
那很吸引你嗎  有個能為你大打出手的男人
And that appeals to you? A man fighting for you?
誰不想找個霸道的男人
Who doesn't want an alpha male?
一個會為他的東西大打出手的男人
A guy who will fight for what's his?
超級火辣
Yeah. Super hot.
聽起來不錯
Sounds exciting.
很酷的  當保羅在追逐蛾子
It's so cool. While Paul chases moths
而珍妮特和她的蜥蜴混在一起的時候
and Jeanette messes around with her lizards,
我正在海島間穿梭觀察海豹
I head out for the islands to watch the seals play.
我不光只有腦子  瞧見沒
I'm not just a brain, see?
我還喜歡玩
I like to play, too.
我是全方位的
I'm the total package.
壞小子  熱辣  全方位
"Badass," "Super hot," "Total package."
全中
Bingo!
是你偽造了約會資料
You wrote the fake dating profile
導致了琳達和她男友分手
that made Linda and her boyfriend break up.
這也沒犯法啊  對吧
No law against it, is there?
也許她發現了是你干的
Maybe she found out it was you,
在實驗室里找你對質  接著事情就失控了
confronted you in the lab, and things got out of hand.
聽著  我沒殺琳達
Look--hello! I didn't kill Linda.
那你為什么要拆散他們
So why did you want to break them up?
你是不知道項目組里的情況
You don't even know what it's like in the program.
基德博士希望我們像歡樂的一家人一樣
Dr. Kidd likes us to play like we're one happy family.
但我們就像一群鬣狗一樣  撕咬著對方
We're like a pack of hyenas tearing each other apart.
為什么
Why?
為了錢  還能為什么
Money. Why else?
博物館里的東西可不是免費得來的
Look, the museum doesn't get all that stuff for free.
它需要各種發現  宣傳和捐助
It needs discoveries, publicity, donations.
基德博士希望我們的項目小組是最棒的
Dr. Kidd wants our program to be the best.
所以如果你沒有成果的話  再見了
So if you aren't producing, so long.
這話是什么意思
What does that mean?
你有沒有聽說過適者生存
You ever heard of survival of the fittest?
基德博士肯定聽說過
'cause Dr. Kidd sure has.
她會淘汰到那些沒有貢獻
She likes to weed out the ones who can't contribute,
不能勝任的人
who can't hack it.
但沒人能勝任  根本沒有
But nobody hacks it. Not really.
什么意思
What do you mean?
珍妮特  那個蜥蜴女
Jeanette? Lizard girl?
你以為她能留下來  她都要急哭了
She has a special place on the back stairs? She goes to cry.
格雷格去年出了大紕漏
Greg had a major breakdown last year,
比如把老鼠骷髏扔到了窗戶外
like throwing rat skulls out the window.
保羅呢  在他發現那該死的蛾子之前
And Paul? He was convinced Dr. Kidd was gonna fire him
他一度確信基德博士就要開除他了
until he discovered that dumb moth.
琳達呢  她是怎么應對的
How about Linda? How did she handle it?
她就像個機器
She was a machine.
我們都快瘋了  她卻什么事都沒有
You're losing your mind, and there she is,
一樣辛苦工作  卻毫不費勁
working just as hard, not even breaking a sweat.
而我呢  因為沒拿到
My mom wanted to kill me
院長的獎學金  我媽差點要殺了我
for not getting the dean's fellowship.
接著琳達遇到了她那個性感的警察男友
And then Linda lands that hot cop boyfriend?
就憑她
Her?
我是說
I mean...
看看
Right?
所以你偽造了約會資料想讓他們分手
So you made up the fake dating profile to break them up.
我只是想看看  我能不能傷到她
I just wanted to see if I could hurt her.
或者她能不能被傷害到
If she could even be hurt.
她知道是你干的嗎
Did she know it was you?
這件事毀了她
It wrecked her.
第二天  她做了一些很愚蠢的事情
The next day she messed up something stupid,
基德博士還朝她大吼來著
and Dr. Kidd yelled at her.
你知道嗎
You know what?
這讓我感覺真的很好
It felt really, really good.
我知道  這讓我聽上去像個壞人
And I know that doesn't make me sound like a nice person.
對  還真不是好人
No. No, it doesn't.
有點像"蠅王"的橋段啊
It's like "Lord of the Flies" over there.
英國作家威廉·戈爾丁的代表作  借小孩的天真來探討人性的惡
我不知道原來科學世界是如此的殘酷
I didn't know the world of science was so cutthroat.
人們不是常說  因為風險極小
Well, like the man said, academic politics
學術政治也會充滿惡意
can be vicious, because the stakes are small.
事實上風險非常小
Very small, indeed.
明天早上我們回博物館一趟
Tomorrow morning we need to go back to the museum.
為什么
Why?
去教育
Education.
但現在我得做些事情
But now I have to do something.
檢察長很清楚  控告不會堅持到最后
And the A.G. knows damn well the indictment won't stick.
我現在沒空和你談
Uh, I don't have time for this.
天下沒有免費的午餐  這道理他懂
Nobody rides for free. I mean, he knows that.
怎么  你過來找我打撲克嗎
What--what, you came here to play games?
我聽說你輸得挺慘
I heard you've been losing,
還影響到了你的工作
and, uh, it's been affecting your work.
我再打給你
Uh, I'll call you back.
撲克根本沒影響我的工作
Look, the cards haven't been falling my way.
得了吧
Oh, come on.
你相信運氣嗎
You believe in luck?
不
No.
里斯本說你很厲害
Lisbon says you're pretty good.
瑪格麗特  取消六點的安排
Margaret, cancel my 6:00.
兩對
Two pair.
四條[四張同點]
Four of a kind.
瞧見沒
See?
我知道怎么玩撲克
I know how to play poker.
你當然知道
Of course you do.
你擅長玩弄人  而不是牌
You play the man, not the cards.
對吧  我懂機率  我了解我自己
Right? I know the odds, I know myself.
你了解人性  知道如何操縱他們
You know people, you know how to control them.
卻不善利用
Not that you always care.
什么意思
Uh... what's that mean?
要多抓蒼蠅  蜂蜜比醋有效
Well, you win more flies with honey than with vinegar,
但你卻非用醋
but you use vinegar anyway.
你是為里斯本來的吧
Is this about Lisbon?
你很喜歡虛張聲勢  是吧
You're very fond of the fake tell, aren't you?
你押注前  會四處張望  緩慢呼氣
Before you bet, you look away and you breathe out very slowly,
看似想讓自己平靜下來
like you're trying to... calm yourself.
沒錯
Yes.
其實你有破綻
Well, you have a tell inside the fake tell.
當你這么做的時候
When you're bluffing,
別人能聽見你的呼吸聲
the breathing is audible.
說什么呢  我能控制住自己
The hell it is. I-I control myself.
你拿到好牌以后  就像那樣呼吸
You get yourself a good hand and puff away like that,
曼徹斯特一定以為你在虛張聲勢
Manchester will for sure think you're bluffing.
相信我
Trust me.
簡先生  有什么可以效勞
Mr. Jane. Can I help you?
但愿吧  你還想學我的記憶訣竅嗎
I hope so. Uh, you still want to learn my memory trick?
當然
I would.
好  你要給琳達的同學們
Yeah, you teach a master class
上研修課的  是吧
with all of Linda's fellow classmates, huh?
今天下午的課  是我和保羅來上
Paul and I will be teaching it this afternoon.
這樣啊
Yeah.
那我給你和你的學生
Well, how about I put on a memory seminar
來場記憶講座如何
for you and your class?
再好不過了
That would be terrific.
不過你不是有謀殺案要破嗎
But don't you have a murder to solve?
來得及
Eh, all in good time.
我需要幾張桌子
Uh, I'm gonna need some tables,
大概三到四張排在那后面
possibly three or four across the back there.
好的
Okay.
還有  琳達的辦公室里有很多動物標本
And, uh, Linda's office, it's full of animals-- dead ones.
是的
It is.
那些也要  做道具用
We'll need access to that, uh, for props.
好的  我猜
Okay. I assume...
你這么做一定另有意圖吧
that you have some ulterior motive for all of this.
你們有懷疑對象了嗎
Do you have a suspect?
有件事我要向你求證一下
There's one thing I'd like you to confirm for me.
什么事
What is that?
北撲翅鴷以什么為食
Just what is the diet of the northern flicker woodpecker?
好的  當然
Yeah. Sure.
你怎么會喜歡三角龍
How can you like Triceratops
而不是霸王龍
more than... T-rex?
霸王龍都是廢物
T-rex are losers.
小胳膊小腿的  不過是長了牙的大型雞
Little arms. It's a big chicken with teeth.
是嗎  那三角龍根本就是長了角的豬
Yeah, and Triceratops is basically a pig with horns.
可它頭上長著盾牌呢
And a shield on its head.
分分鐘秒殺你那巨型雞
Beats a giant chicken any day of the week.
做夢去吧  簡有什么事
Ha ha, in your dreams. What did Jane want?
他叫我們回博物館去
He wants us back at the museum.
回去干嘛
What are we gonna do?
-搶劫博物館  -為什么
- Museum heist. - Why?
我早就不問這些問題了  走吧
I stopped asking questions a long time ago. Come on.
這是干嘛
What's this all about?
我們只是不想有任何遺漏  先生
We just need to cover our bases, sir.
這跟調查有什么關系
What does this have to do with the investigation?
我不能透露在辦案件的細節
I can't discuss ongoing details of an investigation.
我得看看這些蜘蛛
I'm gonna need to look at one of these, uh, spiders.
狼蛛嗎
The tarantulas?
孩子們  來看這些蜘蛛啊
Hey, kids, come check this out. Spiders.
對了  叫狼蛛
Oh, yes. The tarantulas.
我看沒必要吧
I don't see why it is necessary.
別擔心  先生  警方只是例行公事
Don't worry, sir. This is, uh, official police business.
你們一定想看看...
I'm sure you want to take...
等等  你要干嘛
Wait! What are you doing?
-我得近距離觀察一下這只蜘蛛  -不行
- I'm gonna need to take a close look at this spider here. - No.
就是這只蜘蛛
This one specifically here, this spider.
不行  不行  你要干嘛
No, no, what are you doing?
來吧
Here we go.
不行  求你了
Just-- no. Oh, oh, please.
多加小心
Be very careful.
來吧  太好了
There we go. Uh, yeah.
我看沒這個必要吧
I-I don't see why this is necessary.
別害怕  孩子們
Don't worry, children, it's...
好了  來吧
Uh, yeah... there we go.
等等  你在干嘛
Wait, what are you doing?
好了  我們得...
Yeah, we're gonna have to, uh...
-采集它的指紋  -什么
- dust this for prints. - Do what?
顏色真漂亮  是吧  孩子們
Oh, pretty colors. Huh, kids?
我被咬了
It bit--it bit me.
慢著  你說什么
Oh, wait. What?
我被它咬了
It bit me.
我去叫人來吧
Let me call somebody,
這個很危險
this can be a danger.
看  看見沒有  我死定了
Look. See? It's deadly.
我感覺怪怪的
It feels a little strange.
-什么都看不出來  -我頭暈了
- I don't see anything. - Oh, I'm feeling woozy.
沒有  我開玩笑的  我沒事
No, I'm just kidding. I'm fine.
別玩蜘蛛  孩子們  懂了嗎
Don't play with spiders, kids. Okay?
我們今天有福了
We've got a real treat today.
可以稱之為"現實版進化論"
You could call it "Evolution in Action."
派翠克·簡先生將給我們做一場
Mr. Patrick Jane is coming to give us a seminar
有關記憶力上限的講座
on the upper limits of memory.
-我們到教室了吧  -是的  到了
- Are we in the classroom? - Yes, we are.
太棒了
Great.
人類的記憶能力通常比人們意識到的要強
The human memory is far more capable than most people realize.
我之前進過這個房間
I've been in this room once before.
我當時來的時候
But when I was in here...
觀察了一下
I paid attention.
觀察得非常仔細
Very close attention.
謝謝  不過這只是記憶力方面的小兒科
Oh, thank you. Please. But that's just memory 101.
讓我們轉入高級課程吧
Let's move forward into the advanced coursework.
要想記憶力發揮作用
For memory to be useful,
就必須使其如照相機一般精準和迅速
it has to be as accurate and as fast as a camera.
你拿了多少動物  里斯本
How many animals did you get, Lisbon?
大概三十個
Around 30.
是從琳達的辦公室里拿的吧
And you got them from Linda's office?
是  沒錯
Yes, I did.
所有的動物都來自琳達的辦公室
All of the animals came from Linda's office.
之前我從沒去過那兒
That's a place that I have never been.
一會兒  我會回過頭
And in a moment, I will turn around
看我身后的東西  只需要幾秒鐘
and look behind me-- and just for a few seconds--
我就能按順序記住桌上的所有動物
and I will memorize every animal on those tables in order.
然后我會教你們如何做到這一點
And then I will show you how you can do the same.
誰知道你是不是已經背下來了
How do we know you didn't already memorize them?
有個懷疑論者  我該想到的
Ah. A skeptic. I should have known.
不過你說得對
And you're right.
你們沒道理要相信我
There's no reason for you to trust me.
保羅  你能不能把那些動物
Paul, would you mind rearranging the animals
按你認為合適的方式重新擺放
any way you see fit?
沒問題
Sure.
謝謝
Thank you.
人類的大腦
The human brain.
只要運用得當  就能異常高效
Once you get it working right, it can be incredibly effective.
我們的大腦能作出很多不可思議的事情
The mind can do some miraculous things.
比如  預知未來
Uh, like... telling the future.
正如我現在所做的一樣
Which is what I'm doing right now.
吹牛
Bull.
你要是這么說
For that...
就由你來拿著這個預言吧
You can be the one who holds the prediction.
科學就是預言  不是嗎
Science is about prediction, isn't it?
是以確實的數據為基礎的預言  不是算命
Predictions based on hard data, not fortunetelling.
表達不同而已
Ahh. Well, you say "Tomato,"
我認為科學家推崇理性思維
I say scientists believe in rational thought.
表格  列表  分類
And grids and lists and classification,
這些都沒問題  可世界不是這么運轉的
which is fine, but it's not how the world works,
當然大腦也并非如此運轉的
and it's certainly not how the brain works.
你是說人是非理性的嗎
You're saying people aren't rational?
保持理性只是一種手段
Well, being rational is a tool,
但并非我們掌握的唯一手段
but it's not the only tool we have.
早在我們把知識填進圖表前
Long before we stuffed our knowledge into graphs and charts,
我們就用上了很多古老的方式  有時候
we used older and, in some cases,
是更為有趣的方式來記事
more entertaining ways to remember things.
怎么樣了  保羅
How we doing there, Paul?
-好了  -太好了  請坐吧
- I think we're good. - Excellent. Please, take a seat.
現在  我要讓你們見識一下我的理論
Now, I'd like to show you what I'm talking about.
里斯本  勞駕
Lisbon, uh, would you mind?
多謝
Thank you.
我們可以在大腦中建造一座宮殿來幫助記憶
We can create a memory by building a palace in our minds.
我們可以給自己唱首歌
We can sing ourselves a song,
或是講個小故事
or tell ourselves a little story.
這是個惡霸的故事
A story of a bully--
一只灰色的狐貍
a gray fox--
和一個小個子勇士
and a little brave man--
一只老鼠
a rat--
他為他胖乎乎的兄弟癩蛤蟆
that stood up for his chubby little buddy the toad
和他的朋友蛋頭出頭
and his friend egghead.
接著是個穿燕尾服的男人的故事
The story of a man in a tuxedo
他在人群中鉆來鉆去
who snaked his way through a crowd
只為去見一位身著華服的女人
to meet a woman in a colorful dress.
企鵝  蟒蛇  三只松鼠  還有一只鸚鵡
Penguin, cobra, three squirrels, and a parrot.
接著是個關于飛行的故事
The story of flight...
貓頭鷹  蝙蝠  飛蛾
An owl, a bat, a moth,
全部...
All...
看來我說錯了
Ah, I sense I made a mistake.
沒有飛蛾
No moth.
也許我的預言能解釋我犯的錯
Well, perhaps my prediction will explain my error.
珍妮特  請讀出來  好嗎
Uh, Jeanette, could you read it out, please?
飛蛾在保羅的口袋里
"The moth is in Paul's pocket"?
等等  什么
Wait, what?
那只飛蛾
The moth.
那只你重新擺放動物時
The moth you stole from the table
從桌上偷走的飛蛾
when you were rearranging the animals--
在你口袋里面
It's in your pocket.
我需要你清空你的口袋
I'm gonna need you to empty your pockets.
快點
Come on.
讓我們看看
Let's have a look.
保羅  你拿這只飛蛾做什么
Paul, why did you take the moth?
那是只加利福尼亞綠玉蛾
That's a California Jade Moth.
-是的  -這物種是他發現的
- So it is. - The kind he discovered.
我以為唯一的一只收藏在博物館里
I thought the only other one was in the museum.
-那這只是從哪兒來的  -等一下
- Where did that come from? - Wait a second.
你說過所有的動物
You said all the animals
都是從琳達辦公室拿來的
came from Linda's office.
是從那兒拿的
They did.
保羅在琳達死后才發現了這種飛蛾
Linda died before Paul discovered the moth.
這飛蛾不可能是從她辦公室拿的
This moth couldn't have come from her... office.
你會想明白的
You'll get there.
除非  是她先發現的這種飛蛾
Unless... she discovered the moth first.
保羅
Paul...
不會是你殺了琳達吧
You didn't kill Linda.
對  就是他
Yes, he did.
但是  我承認
But, uh, I confess--
那只飛蛾不是我從琳達辦公室拿的
that moth didn't come from Linda's office.
我
I...
偷
s--
我從博物館借出來的
Well, I-I borrowed it from the museum...
為了證明我的觀點
to prove a point.
保羅
Paul.
之前我的論文被退稿了
I'd just had a paper rejected.
被同行評審打回了
Peer review threw it back at me.
基德博士非常失望
Dr. Kidd was so disappointed.
她從沒說過什么
She never said anything.
她也不需要說
She never had to.
琳達的死跟這些事有什么關系
How did Linda come into it?
那天半夜在實驗室里
It was late night at the lab.
她剛剛從森林里回來  非常興奮
Uh, she came in fresh from the forest, excited.
她看到她的一只啄木鳥正在吃一只
Uh, she'd seen one of her woodpeckers eating a moth
她說不出種類的飛蛾
that she couldn't identify.
所以她放了些誘餌并抓住了一只
So she put down some bait and caught one.
我們在她的辦公室找到了紅糖
We found the brown sugar in her office.
就是她的誘餌嗎
Was that her bait?
對
Yeah.
當我看到它的一瞬間我就知道這它是什么
I knew what it was the moment I saw it.
一個新物種
A new species.
它將帶來新文章
I mean, that's articles,
博物館展覽
that's museum exhibits,
為項目帶來資金
that's money for the program.
我看到未來由我自己命名這種飛蛾
I saw myself naming the moth.
我一直都想要給什么東西命名
I'd--I'd always wanted to name something.
我的工作岌岌可危
My job was on the line.
還有我的未來
My future.
我需要這只飛蛾
I needed it...
來度過難關
to survive.
我完全失去了理智
I just lost myself completely.
當我回過神以后
I came back to my senses,
把現場收拾干凈
I cleaned up,
在我們實驗室有很多種清理血跡的方法
lots of ways to clean blood in our lab.
然后  我讓蠕蟲來處理琳達
And then, I gave Linda to the worms.
之后我去了琳達之前
Then I went out to the part of the forest
發現飛蛾的
where I knew she'd been
那片樹林
discovered the moth.
然后回來將這一切據為己有
I came back and got my accolades.
我保住了我的工作
I saved my job.
得到了一切我渴望的東西
I got everything I wanted.
基德博士
Dr. Kidd.
請叫我索尼亞
Sonia, please.
我想要感謝你抓住了保羅
I wanted to thank you for catching Paul.
你不必客氣
Ah. There's no thanks necessary.
琳達死了  保羅進了監獄
Linda's dead, Paul's in jail,
梅根將被開除
and Megan is being expelled.
我想這個項目永遠不會恢復了
I don't think the program will ever recover.
項目并不是真實存在的
The program isn't real.
問題是  你能從中恢復嗎
The question is, will you recover?
我覺得非常無力
I felt so powerless.
我是說  面對死亡你又能做什么呢
I mean, what can you do in the face of death?
但是你并不軟弱無力
You're not powerless, though.
你會行動
You act.
至少你可以做這件事
Well, there's one thing you can do.
保羅通過命名那種飛蛾獲得了很多的榮譽
Uh... Paul took a lot of pride in naming that moth, when...
但實際上應該是琳達來命名它
When it should have been Linda who named it.
沒錯
Yes.
我會確保飛蛾將重新以她來命名
I'll make sure to rename it after her.
謝謝你
Thank you.
是我的榮幸
Pleasure.
對
Yeah.
講得通
Makes sense.
好男人都有主了
All the good ones are taken.
得了吧
Please.
我想是物競天擇
Natural selection, I suppose.
行啦
Come on.
再見  派翠克
Good-bye, Patrick.
再見  索尼亞
Good-bye, Sonia.
跟道金斯五百美元
$500 to Dawkins.
不跟
Nope.
我要
I'll, uh...
加注一百美元
raise $100.
看來我不得不再加注一百美元
Well, I'm just gonna have to raise you another $100.
你怎么就學不會呢  蓋爾
When are you gonna learn, Gale?
再加注一千美元
Raise $1,000.
全押上
All in.
兩對
Two pair.
同花
Flush.
同花更大
Flush takes the pot.
"晚安  月亮"
"Goodnight moon."
以下皆源自美國兒童讀物《晚安  月亮》
"晚安  星星"
"Goodnight stars."
晚安  大法官
Goodnight Judge.
你看到沒  你剛才看到沒
You see that? Did you see that?
同花嗎  非常帶勁
The flush? It was very nice.
我把他贏光了
Ah, I gutted him!
我也這么想
I would say so, yeah.
你很聰明  讓簡來給我上課
That was very slick, you having Jane give me lessons.
看來你真得很想幫范佩爾
You must really want to help Van Pelt.
簡到底做了什么
What did Jane do?
現在就不要再裝了
Oh, now there's no need to be coy.
我會給你回報的
I don't have a problem with a little quid pro quo.
白帽黑客項目  對嗎
The white hat program, wasn't it?
明早我就會批準津貼
I'll authorize the stipend in the morning.
謝謝你  長官
Thank you, Sir.
不  不  多謝你
No, no. Thank you.
-還要謝謝簡  -我會的
- And thank Jane. - I will.
一些科學家認為霸王龍
And some scientists think the T.Rex could run
一小時可以跑45英里[72.4公里]
up to 45 miles an hour.
它是頂級捕食者
That's apex predator.
-你知道這意味著什么嗎  -是的
- You know what that means? - Yes.
這意味著它們是食物鏈的最頂端
That means they're top of the food chain.
-它們能吃掉任何動物  -所以呢
- They eat everything. - So?
所以霸王龍比三角龍更強  我贏了
So... T. Rex beats Triceratops. I win.
你昨晚回家百度了恐龍
You went home last night and googled dinosaurs,
-是不是  -沒錯  我查了
- didn't you? - Yeah, I did.
你連生活都沒  我贏了
You have no life. I win.
我昨天欠她的
I owe her from yesterday.
她正在去機場的路上
She's on her way to the airport.
對  為了那個什么白帽項目的事
Oh. Yeah, for that white hat thing.
不是說沒有津貼嗎
I thought there's no money for that.
里斯本解決了
Lisbon fixed it.
要是能說聲再見就好了
Would have been nice to say good-bye.
對啊  膽小鬼可沒機會
Yeah, well, cowards don't get to say good-bye
說再見
when they want.
膽小...
Cow--wow.
你為什么這么說  你叫我膽小鬼
Where'd that come from? You calling me a coward?
沒錯
Yep.
此話怎講
How so?
你假裝沒有愛著范佩爾
How long have you been pretending
裝了多長時間了
you're not in love with Van Pelt?
誰說我愛著范佩爾了
Who says I'm in love with Van Pelt?
我很久以前有過  但之后再沒有了
I was once, a long time ago, but not anymore.
我們只是  只不過是  好朋友
We're just... we're just... good friends.
你是個膽小鬼和糟糕的騙子
You're a coward and terrible liar.
你胡扯
Uh... says you.
膽小鬼  他懂什么是戀愛嗎
"Coward." What does he know about relationships?
你就跟懷孕的妓女約會
Yeah, well, you date pregnant hookers
而且你的恐龍是吃草的
and your-- your dinosaur eats grass!
-早  -早上好
- Morning. - Good morning.
這段時間我們人手會不夠
We're gonna be short-staffed for a while.
范佩爾啟程去洛杉磯了
Van Pelt's off to L.A.
謝謝你
Thank you.
成人教育是很美好的事
Adult education's a beautiful thing.
說到這
Uh, speaking of which, uh...
我破壞了撲克游戲的生態系統
I've upset the ecosystem of the poker game.
我想你在博物館呆了太久了
I think you've been spending too much time at the museum.
"破壞了生態系統"
"Upset the ecosystem"?
全靠我  伯特侖現在牌技進步了
Bertram's now a better poker player because of me.
生態系統改變了  你要么適應它要么就死亡
The ecosystem has changed. You need to adapt or die.
誰說我需要幫助的
Who says I need the help?
別想跟我耍花招
Don't try to razzle-dazzle me.
有錢能使鬼推磨
Money talks.
我們用什么來做籌碼
What do we use for stakes?
沒有籌碼怎么打撲克
You can't play poker without stakes.
我已經搞定了
Oh, I have that covered.
食草動物算一  食肉動物算五
Herbivores are worth 1, carnivores are worth 5.
好的
Okay.
發牌
Deal.
你有什么牌
What do you got?
全押了
All in.
你在虛張聲勢  我跟注
You're bluffing. I call.
你確定
Really?
好吧  你出老千了嗎
Okay, are you cheating?
沒有
No.
我贏定你了
I'm gonna smoke you.